Sujit Kumar () Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Requirement Gathering, Data Structures, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Algorithms, Jenkins, Python, Oracle, JIRA, Java, Git



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Manhattan Associates Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Requirement Gathering, Data Structures, Spring

Boot, Hibernate, Algorithms, Jenkins, Python, Oracle, JIRA, Java, Git

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Over 6.11 Years of experience in IT Industry as a Software Developer.

Travelled Italy for End to End Support to Client 'Esselunga' for Product Installation and services

Experience of working on Jenkins, GIT, Salesforce and JIRA

Strong Knowledge of working on complex software application (Supply Chain Management System)

Experience on Customization of Complex Module Design and Development

To pursue a challenging career in the Software Development. To work in an environment that appreciates pro-activity and promote work culture that encourages stepping beyond role descriptors.

Work Experience

Manhattan Associates as Senior Software Engineer

Dec 2015 to Till Date

Product: Warehouse Management Open System (Supply Chain Management System)

Clients: Nike, DHL, Walmart, Esselunga, Channel, Sonae

About Product:

Enterprise Order Management Software gives multi-channel retailers and consumer goods manufactures with retail/direct operations the tools to manage, monitor and optimize cross-channel order management from the time of order entry through funding, sourcing, allocation, shipping and settlement. Regardless of whether an order originates online, in-store, through the call center or catalog, multi-channel retail software leverages Manhattan's supply Chain Process Platform to provide a global, real-time view of inventory, order, status and location

Responsibilities:

Co-ordinate with consultants on preparation of functional design document

Prepare technical design document for new modules

Develop new requirements of various client in all modules of WMOS product

Resolve issues pertaining to WMOS product in all the modules

Unit testing and maintaining version control

Technologies: Java, Springboot, Hibernate, JSF, ExtJs, Oracle, Rest, SOAP, JSON, Microservices

Huawei Technology India Pvt. Ltd as Software Engineer

Dec 2013 to Dec 2015

Project: HiLink (WebUI- Datacard software)

Description: Huawei Mobile broadband term used to describe high-speed Internet access from Internet service providers for portable devices. Mobile broadband Data cards allow access of internet at very high speed. Mobile Broadband data card Dashboard provides details of Data usage statistics, USSD, SMS, User call make Calls with Call Feature provided in Dashboard. As well as the firmware interaction with the User Interface and other modules.

Responsibilities:

Customer requirement verification with marketing team Requirement implementation as per customer need

Testing of dashboard in all OS (Windows, Linux, Mac) using test cases provided by test team

Delivery of product within time and deadline

Technologies: Java, Spring, JavaScript, JSF, Ajax

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from APIIT SD INDIA, Panipat in 2013

IT Skills

| Skill Name | Version | Last Used | Experience | |
|------------------------|--------------|-----------|----------------------|--|
| CoreJava | Java SE 8 | 2021 | 3 Year(s) 3 Month(s) | |
| Spring | 4.0 | 2021 | 6 Year(s) 3 Month(s) | |
| Hibernate | 5.2.5 | 2021 | 6 Year(s) 3 Month(s) | |
| ALGORITHMS | | 2021 | 6 Year(s) 3 Month(s) | |
| UML Diagram | 2.2.14 | 2021 | 6 Year(s) 3 Month(s) | |
| Design Patterns | | 2021 | 6 Year(s) 3 Month(s) | |
| Oracle | 11.2.0 | 2021 | 5 Year(s) 2 Month(s) | |
| Data Structures, JBoss | | | | |
| Eclipse, Visual Studio | | | | |
| Apache Tomcat Server, | | | | |

Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English | Proficient | | | |
| Hindi | Expert | | | |

Projects

Project Title: Warehouse Management Open System

Client: World Wide

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2015 - Mar 2017
Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 20

Skill Used: Core Java, Spring, Hibernate, JSF, Dependency Injection

Role Description: 1.Co-ordinate with consultants on preparation of functional design document

2. Prepare technical design document for newly modules

- 3. Develop new requirements of various client in all modules of WMOS product
- 4. Resolve issues pertaining to WMOS product

Project Details: Enterprise Order Management Software gives multi-channel retailers and consumer goods manufactures with retail/direct operations the tools to manage, monitor and optimize cross-channel order management from the time of order entry through funding, sourcing, allocation, shipping and settlement. Regardless of whether an order originates online, instore, through the call center or catalog, multi-channel retail software leverages Manhattans supply Chain Process Platform to provide a global, real-time view of inventory, order, status and location

Project Title: HiLink Client: World Wide

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2013 - Dec 2015

Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 10

Skill Used: Core Java, Spring, JavaScript, JSF, Ajax

Role Description: - Customer requirement verification with marketing team

- Requirement implementation as per customer need
- Testing of dashboard in all OS (Windows, Linux, Mac) using test cases provided by test team
- Delivery of product within time and deadline

Project Details: Huawei Mobile broadband term used to describe high-speed Internet access from Internet service providers for portable devices. Mobile broadband Data cards allow access of internet at very high speed. Mobile Broadband data card Dashboard provides details of Data usage statistics, USSD, SMS, User call make Calls with Call Feature provided in Dashboard. As well as the firmware interaction with the User Interface and other modules.

Affirmative Action

Category: OBC - Creamy

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full time